Hello, welcome to my
true criminal podcast.
As ever, you are very, very welcome.
Today's case is a sad one.
It's about the
disappearance of Joanne Nichols.
Just days before Christmas in 1985,
55-year-old Joanne vanished from her home
in Poughkeepsie, New York.
Her disappearance came a few years
after the devastating
loss of her son, Ticker.
And her husband, James Nichols,
claimed that Joanne was depressed
and that's why she left.
Suspicion did turn to James.
But with no concrete
evidence of foul play,
the case went cold for 27 long years.
It wasn't until 2012,
after James Nichols passed away
and workers began
clearing out the property,
that they uncovered
something hidden inside the house
that would finally reveal
what had happened to Joanne
after all those years.
So let's get on with the story of Joanne
Nichols and the secret behind the wall.
Joanne Nichols, born Joanne Miller, was
born in 1930 and raised
on her family's 240 acre
plantation in Blanchard, Louisiana.
Growing up in a close-knit southern
household, instilled
in her strong values rooted in faith,
tradition, community.
These qualities combined with her deep
compassion for others shaped her
character throughout
her life.
She earned a master's degree in education
from Louisiana State
University in 1955 and
pursued a teaching career.
She had this naturally
caring, warm, nurturing nature.
So teaching really was
the ideal career for her.
And it was while teaching in the small
Mississippi Delta town of
Rolling Fork that she met James
Nichols.
Their relationship blossomed and they
soon married in Shreveport, Louisiana.
Shortly after their wedding, they
welcomed their child James III,
affectionately nicknamed
"Ticker" in 1956.
In 1963, James had secured a
prestigious position with IBM.
So the family moved to Poughkeepsie in
New York where they made
their home on Vassar Road.
Now IBM was a driving
force in the local economy.
It employed thousands of people.
Its influence extended beyond the
workplace, shaping the community and
daily life in the area.
Now as an IBMer, James automatically had
respectability and
trust in the community.
And this becomes important in explaining
how his private world
was largely unquestioned.
How that respectability that he had kind
of overshadowed any
suspicions that people may
have had towards him.
He was seen as somebody safe.
Now Joanne adapted to life in
Poughkeepsie by dedicating
herself to her teaching career.
That same year she began teaching first
grade at Gay Head
Elementary School. Her creativity
and her warmth and dedication quickly
made her a beloved
figure among colleagues and
students and parents.
she had this wonderful innovative
approach to education where she would
roll out a red carpet
for her students making each school day
feel like a special occasion.
You know, teaching
wasn't just a job for Joanne.
It was part of who she was.
She wanted the children to
know how special they were.
And that's because Joanne
was a special lady herself.
She was a devout Southern Baptist
and adhered to her faith's principles,
including things like abstaining from
drinking and smoking
and wearing makeup, that kind of thing.
But her faith, it was
central to her life.
It was a source of strength and support.
It's something that may
have guided her sense of duty,
including her commitment to her marriage.
In 1982, Joanne and James
faced a devastating loss
when their son, Ticker, who at the time
was pursuing a degree
in computer science,
tragically died at the age of 25.
He reportedly fell from his amphicar and
drowned in Sardis Lake, Mississippi.
Now, an amphicar, if you're not sure,
it's like a novelty vehicle
that could drive on land and
water. It's really cute, actually. They
stopped making them in the
60s and they were rare. Even
then in the 80s, they were rare. But it
was tragic because their son died after
driving this amphicar.
Now Joanne and James had very different
grieving styles. Joanne
channeled her grief into her
teaching relying on her faith for
comfort. James responded very
differently. He sold the family
property in Mississippi which he had
envisioned ticker
inheriting one day. But bizarrely,
James also chose to keep the amphicar
that was involved in their son's death.
Now, those things were rare and that
might have been the reason
that he chose to keep it.
But there might have also been an
emotional attachment,
possibly a reminder of his son.
And that was absolutely fine.
Whatever the reason he wanted to keep it,
that was his choice and
his style of grieving.
And that's fine.
But the issue is, he stored
this amphicar in their backyard
where Joanne could see it.
And for Joanne, who grieved differently,
it was a painful,
constant reminder of their loss
that she had to look at all the time.
Now all he had to do was be mindful of
Joanne's hurt and store
this amphicot out of sight,
you know like in a storage unit.
Just be mindful and let his wife grieve
the way that she wanted to grieve.
You know, the loss of a child is often
one of the most devastating
experiences for any couple
and its impact on marital
relationships can be difficult.
And it's even worse when you have two
very different grieving styles going on.
If you can't come
together, that's when riffs appear.
And I'm not saying either
style is right or wrong.
You know, everyone is different,
everyone grieves in their own way,
but it can create misunderstandings,
feelings of
alienation or even resentment.
And there might well have
been resentment from Joanne
because it was James' car.
So even though she
wouldn't have overtly blamed him
for their son's death,
she might have inwardly thought, you
know, it's your car.
If you didn't have that car,
he wouldn't have been on
that lake, that kind of thing.
Besides that, his decision
to keep that amphibious car
clashed with Joanne's
need to distance herself
from painful memories.
And that would have led to
tensions in their relationship.
And it did.
She confided in friends and colleagues
about her frustrations with James.
There were other issues
going on in their marriage.
She complained about
having to hand over her paycheck
to him each week.
This, as we know, strongly suggests
there was a controlling dynamic at home.
We've seen in other cases
how stripping a
person's financial independence
is often a control tactic.
And this need for control by James
extended into another
massive area of their lives.
Joanne was frustrated at his refusal to
declutter their home.
James was a compulsive hoarder. He filled
their property, all of
their property, you know,
including the basement and the garage and
their seven backyard
sheds, seven seems a lot,
but apparently seven backyard sheds, and
he filled it with boxes and
boxes of guns and memorabilia
and tools and cameras and civil war stuff
and random gadgets,
electronics and for cars, you know,
he even store-hood the family's deceased
cat in the freezer. That
is how bad his hoarding was.
He could not let anything go.
I don't know when the hoarding started.
Hoarding is classified as
a psychological disorder
and often stems from underlying emotional
struggles such as
trauma, anxiety or loss.
James's behaviour might have been a
coping mechanism for
unresolved grief after the tragic
loss of his son. Grief can intensify
attachment to objects,
especially when someone struggles
to process loss. His collection to items
that may seem trivial to
other people possibly had
emotional meaning to him. Could his
hoarding have reflected an unconscious
attempt to fill the void
left by his son's absence? It's quite
possible. Now obviously I'm not
diagnosing anybody here,
I'm just giving possibilities as to
things that may have
been going on for him.
Now regardless of what was going on for
James, the impact on Joanne was profound.
She was coping with the
loss of her son herself.
Plus, on top of that, she
had her husband's hoarding.
That was an extra burden on her.
If she was channelling everything into
things like her faith and her teaching,
I imagine that was her way
of creating a sense of order
amongst the chaos going on around her.
But things were
strained in their relationship.
December the 20th 1985. It was five days
before Christmas. Joanne
taught her pupils at Gay Head
Elementary School for the very last time.
That evening she and James
dined with friends at the
ground round grill and bar.
It was a seemingly
ordinary end to the day.
But it was the last time
that anybody saw Joanne alive.
(upbeat music)
The following morning was a Saturday
and Joanne had a hair appointment
scheduled at a local mall.
She didn't turn up.
Later that day, James
Nichols reported his wife missing.
He told detectives he had seen Joanne
earlier that morning
before leaving the house.
He claimed that when he returned home he
found a typed note on his
computer written by Joanne
saying she was depressed over the son's
death. Investigators examined the
computer but the note's
meaning remained inconclusive. In other
words they couldn't tell if Joanne had
written that note or not.
Detective Lieutenant Charles Mittlestadt
later remarked quote "There's a degree of
depression but it's not what I would
consider a suicide letter"
end quote. So it's pretty sus.
A day after Joanne's disappearance
detectives noticed her car had
miraculously appeared on
the driveway. Now her car had not been on
the driveway the previous day.
James claimed he had found her car at a
nearby shopping mall,
but instead of notifying the authorities,
he took the car to be cleaned and
vacuumed, as you do.
Effectively erasing
potential evidence. Crazy.
And it's actually really quite
fascinating behavior
to look at because he must have realized
that cleaning the car
would turn attention on him,
and it did. There are so many
reasons he could have done it.
It could have been pure arrogance,
possibly narcissism,
a sense of internalized entitlement.
He was an IBMer. He was respectable.
Why would people look at him?
That would be his thought process anyway.
It could have been part
of his hoarding behaviors.
Some hoarders
compulsively clean certain objects.
It could have been a way to
regain a sense of control.
Cleaning can be kind of a
way of fixing a situation.
There's loads of reasons why but it's
very very odd behaviour.
Maybe he was just stupid, I don't know.
But ultimately there was
still no sign of Joanne.
In the days that followed, friends and
family grew increasingly worried.
Joanne was known for routine and she
would call her mother
every Sunday between 2 and 4pm
and that Sunday she didn't so people knew
that something was seriously wrong.
Over the following weeks,
officers conducted searches.
They searched waterways and nearby woods.
They searched by foot.
They searched by helicopter.
But there was no trace of Joanne.
They also did a preliminary search of the
Nichols home, walking
through the cluttered rooms.
This was a basic search. It wasn't
thorough, it was
literally just a walkthrough.
But in the basement, James unlocked a
large safe and showed
officers his gun collection.
Again, there's possibly a
few things going on here.
The first thing I
thought was distraction.
Look over there, not
over here. Kind of thing.
Then there's the cooperative performance.
I'm showing you my guns.
I've got nothing to hide.
Kind of thing.
And then as part of his hoarding, a gun
collection fits the
pattern of him collecting things.
But that would also
create a misdirection.
The police didn't immediately see the
house as suspicious.
They saw James as a
collector of things, not a killer.
More than a week after Joanne's
disappearance, James spoke to a reporter
from the Poughkeepsie
Journal. He claimed that Joanne had
called him on Christmas
Eve morning, so about three
days after he reported her missing. He
told the reporter that
she had said she was okay
and asked James to say hello to their two
golden retrievers. When James pressed her
on her whereabouts, she abruptly hung up.
Now, this was
obviously his story, it's what
he told the reporter, but by God, that
was immediately a massive red flag.
If she loved her dogs that much that she
said to him to say hello to them, she
probably wouldn't have left them.
Now, if you're a dog lover, you will
understand what I'm saying.
He continued to tell the reporter, quote,
"There's no reason to assume she's dead
or alive, joined a group or
run off with some other man.
There are a thousand possibilities. The
pain is not knowing." End quote.
Now, the police found absolutely no
evidence that she had even called him
when he said she did.
But the noticeable
thing is his detached tone.
Where's the warmth? His wife is missing.
And he also had inconsistent statements
depending on who he was talking to.
He seemed pretty laid
back with the reporter.
You know, there's a thousand
possibilities why she could be missing.
But he told investigators that Joanne was
depressed and possibly suicidal.
If he genuinely believed that she was
depressed and suicidal, where was the
urgency when talking to the media?
Detective Charles Mittlestadt revealed
that James suggested to the police that
his wife may have run away due to the
pressure of the holiday season.
Which does make sense, that's when a lot
of people, you know,
unfortunately do get very depressed.
But if that's the case, like
I say, where was the urgency?
Why didn't that come across to the media?
He would be saying,
"We need to find her now,
because she's depressed."
Now when James spoke to the police,
according to him, he said
that Joanne had found a new name,
she was at peace with God
and didn't want to be found.
He even claimed that she had left her
wedding ring behind.
You know, his detached tone, the lack of
warmth, the ambiguous remarks,
completely unsettled
investigators, as it would do.
And so they placed
him under surveillance.
Weeks after Joanne's disappearance, they
discovered that James
was seeing another woman.
When they confronted James with
photographs of the two of
them together, he coldly replied,
"If you don't have a warrant for my
arrest, you can talk to my lawyer."
There he is. That is
the real James Nichols.
This marked the last time that James
cooperated with the police.
Now despite the mounting suspicions
against James, the investigations stalled
due to a lack of evidence
without a body, without a weapon,
concrete proof, witnesses, anything.
There was just no evidence of foul play
and detectives were unable
to obtain a search warrant
for the Nichols' home and that's why I
said that initial search
that they did was a preliminary
walkthrough. They needed a search warrant
to do a proper deep search
of his home and that there
is where the system failed. If they had
that search warrant and
went into that home properly
they would have probably found Joanne.
Now it was a source of
frustration for investigators
for Detective Middlestat who strongly
believed Joanne's body was
hidden inside that house.
Middlestat later remarked, "There was no
doubt in my mind that he
knew where his wife was.
The man was cold. I mean seriously cold."
And you know I can't help but wonder,
had James not been this respected middle
class white man working for IBM,
whether things might have been slightly
different. The social
prestige may have shielded James from
scrutiny, not just by the police but
neighbours and acquaintances.
They might have been reluctant
to challenge someone of his perceived
status. It's a phenomenon
seen in many cases where
individuals in positions of authority or
respect are kind of given
the benefit of the doubt even
when warning signs are present. And then
there's also the assumptions about
domestic disputes in
missing persons cases. During that era,
still today but more so
then, cases involving married
couples were frequently seen through the
lens of private personal
conflicts. The husband's
narrative was often accepted without
challenge and this led to a lack of
urgency in investigations.
And then this leads to another issue,
gender bias. Women are
often stereotyped as emotional,
flighty. So there might have been an
assumption that as an
emotional woman she overreacted and
up and left but crucially this bias could
have led investigators to
focusing less on potential crimes
and more on the idea that Joanne left
willingly. I mean I don't know any of
this for certain but it
just seems to me that people from
different backgrounds, different
lifestyles, different
cultures, whatever, can be treated
differently. For instance
people from marginalised groups
such as women of colour or those in
vulnerable socio-economic
situations still often face
slower responses or lower priority.
Now the people who knew Joanne, they all
refused to accept that
she had left voluntarily.
They pointed to her
strange relationship with James.
They said her deep commitment to her
students proved that she
wouldn't have ran away,
she wouldn't have left them and she
wouldn't have taken her own life.
That was just
completely out of character.
In their desperation for answers they
consulted psychics, they
hired private investigators
but all their efforts came to nothing.
The case grew cold and
faded from public attention.
And frustratingly, James Nichols was
never officially named as a suspect
or a person of interest in
his wife's disappearance.
So let's look a
little bit deeper at James.
James Jimmy Lutellus Nicholas Jr. had
always shown unusual behaviour.
He grew up as an only child during the
Great Depression in the small Delta
Hamlet of Alligator, Mississippi.
Alligator took its name from the nearby
Oxbow Lake where
alligators were often seen.
Strangely enough.
I do love useless bits of information.
Now James was the son of a physician and
came from a family of social standing.
A childhood acquaintance
described James as different,
noting that his family was not
affectionate and James
himself lacked warmth.
Now remember the detective who said that
James was cold, seriously cold.
So it's kind of all slotting into place.
Now while other children played games
like cops and robbers,
James preferred to stay indoors and
grossed in his train set.
So that just shows he was a loner.
His interest was more
in things than people.
Again, a characteristic that makes sense.
As James grew older, he developed an
obsession with cars, meticulously
polishing them until they gleamed.
OK, again, sounds very familiar. We can
see the beginning of his obsessive
behaviour and control.
He had a girlfriend, but during games
like musical chairs,
he would pull the
chair out from under her,
causing her to fall.
And this wasn't just once,
it was repeated behavior.
So early on, we have
massive red flag behavior,
pulling a chair out from somebody.
It's not playful, it's humiliating.
It's a way to assert dominance
while kind of
pretending to people it's a joke,
it's supposed to be
funny, but it ain't funny.
It also questions his level of empathy.
Did he have any empathy?
I don't think he did.
It shows difficulties in forming
emotional connections.
It's also socially inappropriate.
You're not fitting in socially
if you're doing that
kind of thing, you know?
And that leads us to
James's behavior in adulthood.
After Joanne disappeared,
he lived an increasingly reclusive life.
He was known to
neighbors for his odd behaviors
and emotionless demeanor
with stories of his eccentricity
spreading throughout the community.
One of his neighbors of
16 years described James
as very strange, explaining, quote,
"I never really saw him that much.
And when we did, he would just be out,
staring without saying hello or
anything," end quote.
Other neighbours shared and settling
accounts of his behaviour over the years.
James was said to drive around with a
mannequin dressed in a hat
seated in the passenger seat.
Now I know you know you just got this
ridiculous mental image of him driving
around with a mannequin
dressed in a hat. It's actually quite
tragic and I wonder whether it was an
attempt at companionship.
He found real emotional connections
difficult so this would have been a
substitute. A mannequin
can't judge, it can't reject, it doesn't
require anything. It's companionship
without risk, you know.
He was said to enter neighbours' homes
without knocking. This
is a clear, clear boundary
violation. It shows he didn't understand
or respect social norms.
He rode his lawnmower around
the neighbourhood with a trailer full of
random items. Now this
kind of seems mundane but he
wasn't masking his eccentricity.
In another incident which was quite a
sinister incident, he killed
an injured squirrel in front
of a neighbour and her terrified children
using a hatchet. Now he was
still dressed in his work tie
and his coat so it's it forms quite an
image of this sort of man
in a suit basically. He's a
respectable man and then he's got a
hatchet and he's chopping up a squirrel
in front of screaming
children and what this shows is a lack of
understanding of how
others feel. You know
most people would know that that would be
distressing to a child but he
didn't seem to understand that.
Another time one of his female neighbours
reported catching James photographing her
with a long lens camera while she painted
her house wearing cut-off shorts.
So we're crossing into creepy predatory
behaviour. And there was
another example of this.
James began dining weekly at a nearby
restaurant called Perkins.
Now a waitress described him as
polite and generous but noted his
unsettling habit of
photographing employees.
His behaviour eventually led to his ban
from the restaurant.
Now, these behaviours solidified James's
reputation as an oddball and a loner.
It was well known in the neighbourhood
that most people avoided him.
And let's just digress for a second and
talk about how society has a habit of
dismissing people who seem
eccentric or socially awkward.
Once somebody is labelled as a loner or a
recluse, their behaviour stops being
questioned and starts being ignored.
And that's exactly
what happened with James.
Neighbours saw his strangeness as
harmless reclusiveness.
His hoarding was treated as an odd quirk
rather than a sign of deeper
psychological issues. People like James
often fall through the cracks.
Their eccentricities camouflage serious
mental health problems and they don't get
the support that they need. And in
extreme cases, James being an example,
strange behaviours and
reclusiveness can be dangerous.
Society teaches us to
leave strange people
alone and for good reason, its
protection, isolation can hide danger.
But it can also hide genuine suffering.
And that's the problem.
How are we supposed
to know which is which?
Is somebody dangerous
or are they suffering?
And that's why communities often don't
know how to respond to eccentricity.
And that's why it shouldn't be ignored
because we don't know which one it is.
And I'm not saying the outcome would have
been different if someone did speak up.
We can't know that.
But early support might
have changed the trajectory.
Who knows?
So just 13 months after Joanne's
disappearance, James filed for divorce.
He cited her absence as the grounds, but
the process was never completed.
When the findings of fact and judgment of
divorce were submitted,
the judge never signed them, leaving the
marriage legally intact.
But think about that 13 months a year.
Does that sound like a man distraught
over his missing wife?
His behaviour is not
that of a grieving husband,
but someone who has already
psychologically moved on.
Now, seven years after Joanne went
missing, she could have
been declared legally dead.
It would have meant somebody applying and
to be clear, James didn't apply for her
to be declared legally dead.
Whether he would have
done, it's possible.
But he never got the chance because as
soon as that seven years hit, Joanne's
family actually intervened and asked the
local court to block the declaration.
And this left Joanne's legal status in
limbo and kept her legally
missing and not deceased.
So the family made sure that James
couldn't declare his wife legally dead,
even if he wanted to.
And what it shows is that Joanne's family
did not trust him one bit.
It was also a way for the family to keep
pressure on the system.
It's signalled that they believed
Joanne's disappearance was not a simple
missing persons case.
Now what the decision actually meant for
James was it prevented
Joanne's share of the property
from transferring to him, effectively
chaining him to the house.
So it helps to explain why he stayed in
the house for so long
because he couldn't sell
it, he couldn't
refinance, he was kind of stuck.
Even if he wanted to, which
psychologically I'm not sure he would
have wanted to, I think
he would have probably stayed there.
But even if he did want to move, it would
have been difficult for him to leave that
house.
So James basically retreated into the
confines of his hoarded home.
He rarely ventured out and
slipped from public attention.
But then, in December 2012, almost 27
years to the day after he
reported his wife missing,
James passed away from
natural causes at the age of 82.
He was found alone in his armchair in the
house he had filled with decades worth of
clutter.
No relatives stepped
forward to claim James's body.
And because of that,
Dutchess County, where they lived,
oversaw his burial
and took responsibility
for managing his estate.
James was buried in an
undisclosed location.
His solitary burial,
kind of a mirror of the
secrecy and the isolation
that he lived in.
James's death marked a turning point
because after nearly three decades,
the mystery surrounding Joanne's
disappearance was
finally about to be solved.
In 2013, a contractor was hired to clear
out James's home on Vassar Road.
As the crew worked through the clutter,
they came across
something no one expected.
Amid the piles of possessions and debris,
the team uncovered a concealed false wall
in the basement. Remember when he was
showing the gun collection? You know,
"Look at my guns. Don't look over there.
Don't look at the false
wall. Look at my guns."
It's really quite sick, isn't it?
Behind the wall lay a
sealed cylindrical barrel.
When the barrel was opened, investigators
found a garbage bag
lightly bound with rope.
Inside the bag were skeletal remains.
Forensic examinations confirmed that the
remains belonged to Joanne.
The Dutchess County Medical Examiner's
Office identified Joanne through
extensive dental work,
including a partial denture which
facilitated
straightforward identification.
So I think it was easy to identify her.
Forensic analysis revealed that Joanne
had died from blunt
force trauma to the head,
with a large area of the
right side of the skull missing,
confirming the
violent nature of her death.
She didn't fall. This wasn't an accident.
Her hands were tied with rope.
This was a violent attack. Her body had
been placed intact in
the container, which was
meticulously insulated to suppress the
odor of decomposition. The
elaborate effort to hide her
body pointed to a deliberate and
calculated attempt to obscure her fate.
As workers continued
to clear out the property, they
discovered the preserved remains of the
two golden retrievers
and the deceased pet cat.
You know, James's death finally revealed
where Joanne was, but
the reason he killed her
died with him. With no confession, no
witnesses, no surviving evidence beyond
the concealed remains,
the motive is never going to be known. In
the absence of
answers, obviously speculation
naturally grew. Could Joanne have been
contemplating leaving him? Was she
frustrated with James's
compulsive hoarding? Was she sick of his
controlling nature? Was
there a confrontation that
spiraled into violence? You know,
possibly all of the above.
There's so many possibilities,
but none can ever be
confirmed. The truth ended with James.
And ultimately, when James concealed
Joanne, he reduced her to yet
another one of his possessions
to be hoarded away.
I mean, what he did was deliberate.
It wasn't an accident and he hoarded her,
you know, because he loved her.
She was just a thing to him.
While her family searched for answers,
desperately searched for
answers, hiring psychics and
private investigators, James ensured that
she stayed beyond
their reach, denying them
the chance to grieve or lay her to rest.
And that's really cruel.
But you know, unresolved cases don't just
affect families, they affect communities.
Their discovery sent shockwaves through
the local community.
Neighbours accustomed to James's
reclusive behaviour were
horrified to learn that he
had concealed Joanne's remains within the
very home that they had passed by daily.
In fact, he was that reclusive.
I think some of the neighbours didn't
even realise he still
lived there, you know.
Either way, it's horrific.
People in her neighbourhood may well have
grappled with guilt.
The missed warning signs, the moments
that they would replay
years later, seeing James
acting oddly.
They would think to themselves, I should
have noticed something.
People remember the unease at the time.
They remember how
uneasy James made them feel.
But most of all, they
remember that nothing was done.
By the time Joanne was finally found,
James Nichols had already died
peacefully, escaping
any criminal accountability.
He died peacefully, which was the
complete opposite to Joanne.
Imagine being one of Joanne's loved ones
and knowing that
justice was never served.
Doesn't seem fair, does it?
James's death also exposed those missed
opportunities that actually allowed
Joanne's disappearance
to remain unsolved for so long.
The police didn't push hard enough.
They didn't push for that
warrant to do a thorough search.
Detective Middlestat, who often drove
past the Nichols' home
wondering whether Joanne's
remains were hidden inside, shared the
frustration. He later said, "It's a sin
that he got away with
it all those years." I probably shouldn't
say this because it's
not politically correct,
but I hope he rots in hell.
politically correct or not, it's correct.
That man deserves to rot in hell and
that's where I hope he is.
After nearly 30 years, Joanne was finally
returned to Louisiana where
she could be laid to rest.
Joanne deserves to be remembered not for
the way she died, but
for the way she lived.
She was a devoted teacher, a woman of
faith, a cherished member of her
community. Her legacy
endures in the students she inspired and
the lives that she touched. And so now,
the red carpet belongs to her, just as
she once made it belong to them.
So that was the case of Joanne Nichols.
It was a really sad case. I usually end
by saying, you know,
be kind, but I want to extend that a
little bit. Be kind to
people who are different.
They might be hurting and a bit of
kindness could change
somebody's day. Vigilance doesn't
always have to mean suspicion, but
equally, you know, don't
ignore behaviour that feels wrong.
You stay safe and hopefully see you back
here for another case at
my true criminal podcast.
Bye.